Norman Holz

E-Mail: norm@nholz.de



CAREER.

I am a Software engineer with over a decade of experience in the technology sector, combining expertise in IT-Systems Engineering and Psychology.

With a foundational education in Software Engineering, I've contributed to diverse projects and clients' success stories, including the development of multiple native and cross-platform mobile applications in various industries, such as banking, social media and health.

My leadership roles have included serving as an Interim CTO and building multiple proficient development teams. I am now leading frontend engineers in their daily work to build the best products for our customers.

EXPERIENCES

Head of Frontend Engineering

FFW Germany GmbH, Hamburg, Germany

May 2022 - Present

- Leading the Frontend Engineering Teams at FFW, I focus on helping my teams (50 FTE) to produce high-quality products. I manage recruitment, advice on technology decisions for pitches and estimates, design trainee programs for emerging frontend developers, and promote an environment fostering innovation and teamwork.
- Management · Front-End Development · Technology Leadership · Software Engineering

Senior Full Stack Engineer

LifeBonus, Hamburg, Germany

Feb 2021 - Apr 2022

- Contributed to a React Native application for caregivers. Introduced a robust video uploading feature for the AI
 department and streamlined user engagement strategies.
- Cloud Computing · React Native · TypeScript · Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Senior Mobile Application Engineer (Freelance)

Hanseatic Bank, Hamburg, Germany

Apr 2012 - Jul 2014

- Collaborated on the development of a credit card self-service app using React Native. Achievements include
 integrating mobile payment solutions, like Apple Pay and onboarding and maturing a proficient in-house
 development team.
- React Native · TypeScript · Apple Pay · Google Pay · Mobile Application Development

Interim Chief Technology Officer (Freelance)

Hamburg Startups, Hamburg, Germany

May 2016 - Dec 2018

- Oversaw software development and infrastructure maintenance. Introduced a multi-tenancy framework and advised on product strategy shifts.
- Backbone.js · Technology Leadership · Linux System Administration · JavaScript · Python

Senior iOS Engineer (Freelance)

Group Story Social Media Platform, Hamburg, Germany

Apr 2016 - Apr 2018

 Collaborated on refining a mobile application. Highlights include implementing an in-app video editing solution and optimizing video upload functionalities. - Swift · Video Processing · Mobile Application Development · Objective-C · iOS Development

Staff Software Engineer

Complete Genomics Inc., Mountain View, CA, USA

Oct 2014 - Jan 2016

- Contributed to the field of genetic data analysis. Responsibilities included building and optimizing large data
 processing pipelines and assisting the scientific community with data analysis.
- Cloud Computing · Big Data · JavaScript · Node.js · MongoDB · Python

Software Engineer

Q-vi Tech GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Jan 2011 - Sep 2014

- Developed Java-based model transformation, validation, and documentation tools for CARIAD SE and led the creation of Eventoo, a location based event suggestion App for iOS.
- AUTOSAR · Java · Objective-C · iOS Development

Software Engineering Intern

SAP Labs, Palo Alto, CA, USA

May 2010 - Dec 2010

- Contributed to a Java-based prototype for social media sentiment analysis and developed iOS prototypes for SAP's software sales consultants within the Office of the CTO.
- Java · Objective-C · iOS Development

Student intern

SAP, Berlin, Germany

Aug 2007 - Jul 2009

- Participated in developing a software architecture analysis tool, optimizing SAP's product offerings by generating detailed architecture reports using Java, XML, and XSLT.
- XML \cdot XML Schema \cdot XSLT \cdot Java

Student intern

DaimlerChrysler, Berlin, Germany

Mar 2006 - Jul 2009

- Developed a bridge in Java to integrate C++ libraries with Java programs, enhancing cross-language compatibility and library communication.
- Java, C++, JNI

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Psychology

FernUniversität in Hagen

2018 - 2022

 Specialization in Work and Organizational Psychology. Bachelor's Thesis on Influencer Entrepreneurship and the Role of Power Motive.

M.Sc. IT-Systems Engineering

HPI — University of Potsdam

2007 - 2010

 Focused on Systems Architecture, Human-Computer Interaction, and Computer Graphics. Master's Thesis on Out-of-Core Rendering of Remote 3D Virtual Environments on Mobile Devices.

B.Sc. IT-Systems Engineering

HPI — University of Potsdam

2005 - 2007

 Concentrated on Internet Technologies and Human-Computer Interfaces. Bachelor's Project on Design and Implementation of an Online Portal for Multimedia Books.

Languages

• German: Native

• English: Fluent (C2 proficiency)